guggenheim.org 2014-11-12

# Privacy Policy

#### Introduction

The Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation (the “Guggenheim”) is committed to protecting the privacy of its website visitors in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. All information gathered from you in connection with your use of the www.guggenheim.org website, the http://blogs.guggenheim.org/ website, the www.bmwguggenheimlab.org website and the guggenheimstore.org website, as well as various microsites that include .guggenheim.org or .bmwguggenheimlab.org in the URL, and related services, including RSS feeds, mobile websites and mobile applications (such services, collectively, referred to herein as the “Site”) is governed by this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”). By using the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

#### Collection of Information by the Guggenheim

The Guggenheim does not systematically collect or record names, postal or e-mail addresses, phone numbers, gender identity, or other personally identifying data (the “Personal Data”) from visitors to the Site, unless such data is voluntarily submitted by visitors for the purposes outlined below.

##### Cookies and Aggregate Information

The Guggenheim uses "cookies" (i.e., a small text file that is sent to your browser from the Site) to improve your return access and visits to the Site. The Guggenheim may use cookies to customize content, to analyze Site activity and user behavior, including, without limitation, through Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, and for advertising and promotional purposes (further discussed in “Interest-based Advertising” below). The Guggenheim reserves the right to use cookies in the future in conjunction with new or extended functionalities.

The Guggenheim may compile and provide aggregate statistics about Site visitors, customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related information to third parties, but such information will not specify Personal Data. The Guggenheim collects IP addresses as a component of such aggregate information. Such information could, if necessary, be used to identify a user in order to comply with safety or security issues.

You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie (letting you choose whether to accept it) or to disallow cookies altogether, without preventing your access to the Site.

##### Interest Based Advertising

The Guggenheim may provide certain third party service providers, including Google Analytics Remarketing, the cookies it has obtained in order for such service provider to inform, optimize and serve advertisements on other websites a user visits, based on such user’s prior visits to the Site. The Guggenheim directs these service providers to not use the provided cookies for any purpose other than to provide the advertising services explicitly requested by the Guggenheim.

You can opt out of certain service providers’ use of cookies. For example:

  * Google permits you to register your preferences at <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>;
  * Google Analytics also provides an opt-out add-on for your browser ([https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/ "tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/");
  * The Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices>) and the National Advertising Initiative ([http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices "networkadvertising.org/choices")) have websites that allow you to register your choice to opt-out of receiving interest-based advertisements from certain companies that participate in such initiatives

##### Online Mailing Lists and E-news

From time to time, the Guggenheim may offer Site visitors the opportunity to subscribe to one or more online mailing lists and e-news. If you choose to subscribe, the Guggenheim or its third-party service provider will request such information, including Personal Data, as is necessary to process your subscription. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Sharing of Personal Data with Others." You may subscribe or unsubscribe at any time by following the associated instructions.

If you subscribe to our online mailing lists and e-news through ExactTarget, a third-party service provider, ExactTarget’s independent privacy policy governs its use of Personal Data. Please consult the [ExactTarget Privacy Policy](http://www.exacttarget.com/privacy-policy) for more information.

In addition to the foregoing, please note that if you opt-in to subscribing to our online mailing list(s) and/or signing up for e-news by accessing WiFi at the Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum through Socialsign.in, a third-party service provider, Socialsign.in’s independent privacy policy governs its use of Personal Data. Please consult the [Socialsign.in Privacy Policy](http://socialsign.in/privacy) for more information.

##### Online Donations and Memberships

When you make a donation or purchase a Guggenheim Museum membership online through the Site, the Guggenheim and its third-party merchants and agents will request information necessary to process your membership or acknowledge your contribution: your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. Your credit card information will be used only for the purpose of processing and documenting the transaction. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Sharing of Personal Data with Others."

Please note that when you make an online donation or purchase a Guggenheim membership online, you exit the Site and enter the site of Blackbaud, a third-party service provider. Blackbaud has an independent privacy policy that governs Blackbaud’s use of Personal Data, which is collected during your purchase. Please consult the [Blackbaud Privacy Policy](http://www.blackbaud.com/privacy/overview.aspx "Blackbaud Privacy Policy") for more information.

##### Online Store Purchases

When you order a product from the Guggenheim Museum "Online Store," the Guggenheim and its third-party merchants and agents will request information necessary to process your order: your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. Your credit card information will be used only for the purpose of processing and documenting the transaction. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Sharing of Personal Data with Others."

##### Online Admissions and Event Registrations and Tickets

When you purchase online tickets through the Site (including tickets for admission to the Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, special exhibitions, performances, lectures, and other educational programs offered by the Guggenheim), the Guggenheim and its third-party merchants and agents will request information necessary to process your order: your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. Your credit card information will be used only for the purpose of processing and documenting the transaction. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Sharing of Personal Data with Others."

Please note that when you purchase a Guggenheim ticket online, you exit the Site and enter the site of our ticket agents Museumtix.com or Tix. Museumtix.com and Tix have independent privacy policies that govern their use of Personal Data, which is collected during your purchase. Please consult the [Museumtix.com](http://www.museumtix.com/help/PurchasePolicy.aspx?pvt=srgf "Museumtix.com") and [Tix](http://guggenheim.tix.com/Privacy.asp "Tix") privacy policies for more information.

Please note that when you register and/or pay for certain events, NetCommunity run by Blackbaud, a third-party service provider, may collect Personal Data. Blackbaud has an independent privacy policy that governs its use of Personal Data. Please consult the [Blackbaud Privacy Policy](https://www.blackbaud.com/privacy-policy.aspx) for more information.

##### E-Cards

The Guggenheim offers its Site visitors the opportunity to send E-Cards featuring images from the collection, exhibitions, and architecture. When you send an E-Card, you will need to provide your name and e-mail address, as well as the recipient’s name and e-mail address. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Sharing of Personal Data with Others."

Please note that this service is made possible through a third-party merchant, Truelogic. The Terms and Conditions governing E-Cards may be accessed directly on the [E-Cards](http://guggenheim.corporateecards.com/ "guggenheim.corporateecards.com") section of the Site.

##### Online Surveys

From time to time, the Guggenheim may offer Site visitors the opportunity to participate in an online survey. If you choose to participate, the Guggenheim or its third-party affiliate will request such information, including Personal Data, as is necessary to process your survey results. The terms of this Privacy Policy shall apply to such surveys, unless the Guggenheim or its third-party affiliate provides an alternate policy governing the use of Personal Data collected from such survey. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Disclosure of Personal Data to Others."

##### Online Auctions, Contests, and Sweepstakes

From time to time, the Guggenheim may offer Site visitors the opportunity to participate in an online auction, contest, or sweepstakes. If you choose to participate, the Guggenheim or its third-party affiliate will request such information, including Personal Data, as is necessary for such participation. The terms of this Privacy Policy shall apply to such information, unless the Guggenheim or its third-party affiliate provides an alternate policy governing the use of Personal Data collected from such auction, contest, or sweepstakes. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Disclosure of Personal Data to Others."

##### User-Generated Content

From time to time, the Guggenheim may offer Site visitors the opportunity to submit content or post comments. If you choose to participate, the Guggenheim or its third-party affiliate will request such information, including Personal Data, as is necessary for such participation. The terms of this Privacy Policy shall apply to such information, unless the Guggenheim or its third-party affiliate provides an alternate policy governing the use of Personal Data collected from such user submission. Your Personal Data may be used as set forth below. See "Use of Personal Data by the Guggenheim" and "Disclosure of Personal Data to Others."

#### USE OF PERSONAL DATA BY THE GUGGENHEIM

The Guggenheim uses the personal information you provide to us for internal purposes, such as filling and tracking your order, analyzing trends and collecting statistics. In addition, the Guggenheim may use your Personal Data for Guggenheim marketing and promotional purposes. For example, the Guggenheim may notify you of events, programs, sales at the Guggenheim Store, and special offers and promotions related to the Guggenheim Museum that we think might be of interest to you. We may also request your participation in surveys. If you do not want us to use your Personal Data to contact you for these purposes, please follow the instructions in “Do Not Contact” below.

#### SHARING OF PERSONAL DATA WITH OTHERS

##### Personal Data

The Guggenheim may share your Personal Data, as collected under the circumstances outlined above, with other reputable organizations, such as other nonprofits, art institutions, and media companies.

The Guggenheim has teamed up with reputable third-party vendors in order to provide certain services to its online users and allow us to better respond to the needs of our visitors. The Guggenheim requires its vendors to maintain the confidentiality and security of the information to which they are provided access, and restricts these vendors from using the information in any way without express authorization by the Guggenheim.

##### Credit Cards

The Guggenheim will not share, rent, or sell your credit card information to third parties.

#### Linking to third parties

The Site may include links to websites operated by third parties over which the Guggenheim has no control. Once you leave the Site, this Privacy Policy will no longer apply, and you will be subject to the third party’s privacy policy. For example, the Guggenheim may use third-party service providers such as Facebook and Twitter to give you easy ways to share our content with others. The information you provide when using these tools is subject to these third parties' privacy policies. The Guggenheim is not responsible for the privacy or security practices nor the content of third party websites, and such links are not intended to be an endorsement of the third party website or its content.

#### Children Under Thirteen Years Old

Please note that the Site is not specifically dedicated to use by children and the Guggenheim does not actively solicit information from children. Children under the age of 13 are required to obtain permission from a guardian before submitting information to the Site.

#### Site Security

The Guggenheim secure server software uses industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology for certain on-line financial transactions. SSL encodes your personal data, including credit card name and number, as it travels over the Internet so that these transactions are secure. If you prefer, you may also place an order with the [Guggenheim Museum Online Store](http://www.guggenheimstore.org/ "Guggenheim Museum Online Store") by calling 800 329 6109. You may purchase a membership by calling 212 423 3535. You may inquire about making a donation by calling 212 423 3624.

#### Do Not Contact

If you do not want to be contacted by the Guggenheim, or if you do not want the Guggenheim to share your Personal Data, please let us know by writing to [donotcontact@guggenheim.org](mailto:donotcontact@guggenheim.org "donotcontact@guggenheim.org") or to the following address:

The Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation  
345 Hudson Street, 12th Floor  
New York, NY 10014  
Attn: Marketing – Do Not Contact List

#### Revisions to our Privacy Policy

The Guggenheim may revise its Privacy Policy at any time, without notice, and encourages you to periodically visit this page to review the most current policy.

#### Contact Information

You may send comments or questions about this Privacy Policy to [privacy@guggenheim.org](mailto:privacy@guggenheim.org "privacy@guggenheim.org").

Effective Date: 9/15/08  
Updated: 01/14/14

© The Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation, New York. All rights reserved.
